>> Brian Holt: 前面提到的所有这些部分都将转至
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: All these sections like I
was alluding to previously are going to
除了第一个忏悔的人之外
have to do with one repo,
except the first one.
我们要做的第一个是深度的胡克丝
The first one that we're gonna
do here is Hooks in Depth.
这实际上是在一个代码沙箱上
And this is actually going
to be on a code sandbox,
就像 CodePen 或 JSBin 或类似的东西
which is like a CodePen or
JSBin or something like that.
那么，请在此处单击 " 深度 " 中的 " 挂钩 " 。
So, go ahead and
click in to Hooks in Depth here.
打开此链接，在该链接中，打开此链接是代码沙箱，
And open this link in where it
says open this is code sandbox,
只要打开它就可以了
just open that link there.
所以在第 V5 React V5 的完整简介中，我们将进入 " 使用状态" ，
So in the Complete Intro to React V5,
we go over useState,
useEffect， useContext 和 useRef。
useEffect, useContext, and useRef.
我们把部分的 useRef ，不是全部都去了。
We go over parts of useRef, not all of it.
但这三个都被覆盖了
But these three are pretty well covered.
useState， useEffect和 useContext。
useState, useEffect, and useContext.
我们会再过去的但是你知道
We'll go over them again,
but just so you know,
如果你经历了这一过程你至少应该明白这一点
if you've gone through that course, you
should understand at least most of that.
用这四个钩子
Using these four hooks,
我只是想说你能解决 99% 的问题
I'm just going to assert that you
can cover 99% of your problems.
大概 100% 的问题， [LAUGH] 是吧 ?
Maybe 100% of your problems,
[LAUGH] right?
另一个是你可能使用的其他钩子的长尾巴
The other ones are kind of a long tail of
other hooks that you could possibly use,
但我要教你怎么做
but I'm going to show
you how to do it anyway.
你可以看到我有每个钩子
So in here you can see
that I have each hook,
我直接链接到组件，然后对其进行说明。
I link directly into the component and
then there's an explanation of it.
所以，如果你想跟上它，那就是我们要做的。
So if you want to keep up with it,
that's what we're going to do.
我们不打算写任何代码，这都是我的
We're not going to actually write any
code, this is all just going to be me
通过在上面写的密码说话
talking through the code that's
already written up there.
你在这里看到的是有一个项目有一堆
What you see in front of you here is
there's a project that has a bunch of
这里的不同组件
different components here.
然后它有一个应用页面来呈现各种不同的事物。
And then it has one app page that renders
out all of these various different things.
所以我们要用一块过去的
So we're just going to go
through piece by piece and
谈论每个人的钩子和他们的行为
talk about each individual hook and
what they do.
所以您可以在这里看到 index.js ，它会呈现一个组件，并且
So you can see here the index.js,
all it does is it renders a component, and
那么它就会有一个小时，这是一个横向的规则，就是这里的线。
then it does a hr, which is a horizontal
rule, which is the line here.
它是一个 HTML 组件，或者是一个标签，一个旧的。
It's a HTML component, or
a tag rather, an old one at that.
好吗 ?
Okay?
那么让我们来看第一个，就是国家，
So let's go take a look at the first one,
which is state,
这里有全州的
which is state.js over here.
>> Brian Holt: 这是第一次点击，如果点击
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: And it's this first
one here where if you click on
它改变了颜色
it it changes colors.
Magical，对吧 ?
Magical, right?
让我们来谈谈规范这个问题的代码。
So let's talk about
the code that governs that.
>> Brian Holt: 使其更小。
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: Make this a lot smaller.
好了我们从雷法进口了 React 和 useState
Okay, so here we're importing React and
useState from React.
这个有状态的组件，就是一个箭头函数，对。
And this stateful component,
which is just a arrow function, right.
我们正在使用使用状态，我们正在将初始状态设置为 true，对。
We're using useState and we're setting
the initial state to be true, right.
所以你第一次得到绿绿的时候就意味着
So that means on the first
time that you get isGreen,
艾格林会是真的对吧
isGreen is going to be true, right.
但这只适用于非常非常的第一次，这是默认状态。
But that's only applicable on the very,
very first time, it's the default state.
之后的一切都是一个国家的容器
Everything after that,
it's a state container, so
它会随着时间的推移而保持状态
it's keeping track of state over time.
所以钩子会回到一对，一个元组，一个元组，不管你想说什么。
So hook comes back in a pair, a tuple,
a tuple, whatever you wanna call it.
在 JavaScript 中，它是两个数组。
In JavaScript, it's an array of two.
在 JavaScript 中没有特殊的数据结构但是在 Python中
There's no special data structure for
this in JavaScript, but in Python,
有，对吧 ?
there is, right?
或者哈斯凯尔之类的
Or Haskell or something like that.
这就是破坏
So this is destructuring out.
所以第一件事是我们要跟踪的实际情况。
So the first thing is the actual piece of
state that we're going to keep track of.
第二个是更新那个状态的功能。
And the second thing is a function
to update that piece of state.
这是第一次呈现绿色。
So here it's green on the first render.
如果我们在这里刷新页面，您可以在首次呈现时看到它是绿色的。
If we were to refresh the page here,
You can see it's green on first render.
所以艾格林是真的，对吧 ?
So isGreen is true, right?
我们现在正在做的是说颜色是绿色的，然后放绿色。
And here all we're doing is saying if
the color is green, then put lime green.
如果不是的话就放了克里姆森
If it's not, then put crimson.
所以如果我点击它，我就把这个功能叫做 " 绿色 "
So if I click on it, then I call this
function here that says set green to
正好相反的是什么是绿色的对吧
be the opposite of whatever isGreen was,
right?
所以现在是 " 绿色 " 是真的
So right now isGreen is true.
所以我称这个 onClick 处理程序，它会将它设置为 false，对吗 ?
So I call this onClick handler,
it's gonna to set this to be false, right?
而且，如果我点击它，它会变成红色。
And lo and behold,
if I click on it, it turns to red.
>> Brian Holt: 请记住，您可以在一个功能中像您一样多挂钩
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: Keep in mind you can have
as many hooks in one function as you
可能是想，对吧 ?
possibly want, right?
因此，我可以有多个不同的状态。
So I can have multiple
different pieces of state.
每个人都有自己的更新功能
And each one of them can have
their own updater function.
再一次
So again,
挂钩的主要规则之一是它们不能在条件中。
one of the cardinal rule of hooks is
they cannot be inside of conditionals.
它们不能用于循环或任何类似的情况。
They cannot be inside of for
loops or anything like that.
他们总是要打电话，因为很，很有条件，
They always have to be called,
because it's very, very contingent on or
取决于它是否每个时间都在同一顺序中。
dependent on it being in
the same order every single time.
所以如果我打十个电话的话我要用同样的顺序来称呼它
So if I call useState ten times, I need to
call it in the exact same order, every,
就像 10 次一样
like all ten times.